Paul Muldoon papers, 1939-2010
Emory University
- Writings by Muldoon, circa 1960s-2004, Series 2; Boxes 8-30, 66-84 and OP 2-9, 163-167
  - Dramatic works and lyrics, 1970s-2000s, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 24-27, 74-77 and OP 166-167
    - Sister Carrie, a preliminary treatment by Paul Muldoon and Tobias Picker, typescript fragments, 1999 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Six Honest Serving Men, lightly corrected typescript fragment (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Ambient Starlight [variant title Six Honest Serving Men], typescript draft with holograph corrections (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Six Honest Serving Men, photocopy of uncorrected typescript including Glossary (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Six Honest Serving Men, uncorrected typescript in yellow binder (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Six Honest Serving Men, page proofs (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Vera of Las Vegas, corrected typescript of title page and Dramatis Personae list (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Vera of Las Vegas: A Nightmare Cabaret Opera in One Act, by Daron Hagen, libretto by Paul Muldoon, typescript of title page and contents (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Vera of Las Vegas, proofs, February 28, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Vera of Las Vegas, typescript (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Shining Brow (1993)
    - Shining Brow, fragment including "The Workmen's Chorus from "Shining Brow" (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - One page holograph note in Muldoon's hand (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Photocopies of historical background (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Loose and unsorted holograph notes (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Typescript fragment (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Typescript fragment with extensive corrections and holograph notes (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Two corrected typescript fragments (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Corrected typescript fragment with holograph notes (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Typescript fragments with extensive holograph corrections (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Writing tablet with holograph notes (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Loose corrected typescript (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Loose corrected typescript with manila envelope (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Typescript with very minimal corrections (circa 158 pages) (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Act One, "Version November 27, 1990," corrected typescript (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Prologue and Act One, "January 20, 1991, NYC," typescript (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Character List, Prologue, and Scene One, uncorrected typescript (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Act Two typescript with holograph corrected by Muldoon and Hagen, labeled "Daron's Working Draft" (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Act Two, corrected typescript (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Act Two, corrected typescript (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Act Two, Scene Four, multiple corrected typescripts (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Act Two, multiple corrected typescripts for portion of second act (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Act Two, Scene Three, corrected typescript fragment (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Act Two, Scenes Two and Three, corrected typescript fragment with holograph notes (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Act Two, Scenes Two and Three, corrected typescript (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - The Shining Brow, treatment, original typescript with single holograph correction and hand-written page numbers (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Treatment, photocopy of typescript with single holograph correction (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Treatment, photocopy of typescript with single holograph correction (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Treatment, photocopy of typescript with single holograph correction (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Treatment, photocopy of typescript with single holograph correction (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Treatment, photocopy of typescript with single holograph correction (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Synopsis/brief treatment, typescript (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Treatment, photocopy of typescript with extensive holograph corrections, labeled "Master Copy" (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - "Working Libretto" for The Shining Brow, dated July 1, 1991, uncorrected typescript (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Ribbon typescript in red binder with holograph corrections (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Ribbon typescript in blue binder with holograph corrections (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Page proofs with holograph corrections and letter to Charles Boyle re: revision (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Photocopy of page proofs with holograph corrections (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Photocopy of score by Daron Hagen (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Ring-bound copy of piano/vocal score, labeled "Version #5," [1 of 2] (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Ring-bound copy of piano/vocal score, labeled "Version #5," [2 of 2] (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Ring-bound copy piano/vocal score, final copy(?) (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - The Shining Brow, notes to Hagen re: revisions, dated May 17, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy proof of Act One (music and lyrics) with holograph corrections (pp. 1-44) (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy proof of Act One (music and lyrics) with holograph corrections (pp. 45-81) (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - "Proof Reduction" of Act One Prologue, with light holograph corrections (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - "Taliesin: Choruses from Shining Brow," bound vocal score (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Shining Brow: Daron Hagen correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Shining Brow correspondence (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Shining Brow correspondence, continued (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Congratulatory notes from Madison, Wisconsin premiere of Shining Brow (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Publicity materials, including programs, brochures, letters, and press release drafts (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous clippings re: Shining Brow (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Faber contract re: Shining Brow (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - "Muldoon Songs," photocopy of vocal score proofs with holograph corrections (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - The Waking Father, by Daron Aric Hagen, words by Paul Muldoon, photocopy dated 1994 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Bandanna (1999)
    - "Prologue," typescript fragments (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - "Act I," typescript fragments (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - "Act II," typescript fragments and notes (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - "An Opera in Two Acts and a Prologue," partial typescripts (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Complete typescript (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Numbered typescript (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - "Paul Muldoon on Bandanna," typescript, 1998 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Scene sketches, typescripts, 1997 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Work copy, Hagen (Box OP166)
    - Work copy, Muldoon (Box OP167)
    - "Working Libretto," January 11, 1998 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - "Working Libretto," May 1998 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Contracts, 1997-1999 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with Daron Hagen, 1997 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with Daron Hagen, January-February 1998 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Daron Hagen, March 1998-July 2004 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with publishers, 1998-1999 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Publicity, promotional material, and reviews, 1998-1999 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Daron Hagen Correspondence, general
    - 1995-1996, with proof of working copy of libretto, Vera of Las Vegas (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Hagen, Daron, 1997-1999, with typescript of article, "Singing Along, With Paul," by Hagen about collaborating with Paul Muldoon (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Hagen, Daron, 2000-2004, with typescript interview of Hagen, about collaborating with Muldoon on Bandanna (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Rackett (band) [lyrics with Rob Mathes]
    - "Always Stay," "American Lives," and "Brighton Rock," typescripts (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - "Comeback," typescripts (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - "Come Close," typescripts (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - "Critical Mass," "Cry Baby Cry," and "Don't Try This at Home," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - "Don't Think for a Minute" and "Enough of Me," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - "Face Time," "Go Between," and "Going Through the Hoops," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - "Hard Cheese and Sour Grapes," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - "Head In," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - "Her Name Is Jean," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - "I Might Make Out with You," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - "I Want to Get Down and Dirty," "Kickstart the Electra Glide," and "Like It Is," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - "Meat and Drink," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - "Need to Know," typescripts and notes (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - "(Now I've Put My) Faith in You," "Old Flames," "One Too Many," and "Only Thing," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - "Over You," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - "Pencil" and "Princeton Reverb," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - "Rock Steady," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - "Saab with Sandy," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - "Standing Room Only," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - "Take It as Gospel" and "Twice on Clay," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - "Who Knew That My Love?", "Wrong Man," and "You Gotta Take Out Milt," typescripts (Box 77, Folder 18)
  - Translations, 1983-2002, Subseries 2.3; Boxes 28 and 78
    The subseries consists of typescript drafts of poems written by others and translated by Muldoon from 1983-2002. Some files also contain copies of the poems in their original language.
    Materials are arranged loosely in alphabetical order.
    - The Astrakhan Cloak, poems by Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill, versions by Paul Muldoon, photocopies of original Irish poems with lightly corrected typescripts of translations (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Translations of poems by Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill with extensive holograph corrections and notes in Ní Dhomhnaill's hand re: concerns raised by Dillon Johnston (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Photocopies of poems by Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill with initial notes for translation (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - "The Drowned Blackbird": Translations from the Irish, typescript of translations of poems by Seamus Dall MacCuarta with some holograph notes re: formatting [also Miscellaneous Poems, circa 1983-1986] (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - "Gan Do Chuid Éadaigh," photocopy with "crib" for translation and holograph notes (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Marin Sorescu, photocopies related to Muldoon's translations for The Biggest Egg in the World [See also Subseries 2.1: Miscellaneous Poems, ca. 1983-1986, "Precautions"] (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Thirteen poems by Marin Sorescu, translated by Paul Muldoon (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Michael Davitt, Three Poems by Michael Davitt, translated by Paul Muldoon, photocopy of typescript with holograph corrections (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Aristophanes, The Birds, translated by Muldoon with Richard Martin, annotated glosses (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Aristophanes, The Birds, translated by Muldoon with Richard Martin, complete typescript [1 of 2] (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Aristophanes, The Birds, translated by Muldoon with Richard Martin, complete typescript [2 of 2] (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Aristophanes, The Birds, translated by Muldoon with Richard Martin, loose typescript pages and notes (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Aristophanes, The Birds, translated by Muldoon with Richard Martin, partial typescripts (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Aristophanes, The Birds, translated by Muldoon with Richard Martin, proofs, May 5, 1999 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Joseph Brodsky, "Snow Is Falling," typescripts, circa 2000 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - "Cnaimhin Sugartha (sceal na nathrac)" ("The Bliss Bone"), typescripts (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Michael Davitt, Freacnairc Mhearcair (The Oomph of Quicksilver), page proofs, June 2000 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Michael Davitt, "Glaoch" ("Call"), typescripts (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - The Hebrew Book of Psalms, with Michael Davis, typescripts (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Horace: Odes, translated by Paul Muldoon, January 1, 2001 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Kutna Hora, "At the Bonehouse," typescript, 2002 (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Seamus Dall MacCuarta, "An Lon Dubh Baite" ("The Drowned Blackbird"), typescript (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Manuel Vazquez Montalban, two poems translated by Paul Muldoon and Jordi Doce, typescripts (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - Liam a Muirthile, "An Bosca Uirlis," "An Dibeartach," and "Dreimire," typescripts, 1997 (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - Pablo Neruda, "Ode to a Hare-Boy," typescript, October 13, 2002 (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill, "An Obair" ("The Task"), typescript (Box 78, Folder 18)
    - Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill, "Dan Molta Prosac" ("Poem in Praise of Prosac"), typescript (Box 78, Folder 19)
    - Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill, "Dubh," typescripts (Box 78, Folder 20)
    - Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill, The Fifty Minute Mermaid, "The Assimilated Merfolk" ("Na Murucha a Thriomaigh"), typescripts (Box 78, Folder 21)
    - Unidentified poet, "Red," page proof (Box 78, Folder 22)
  - Children's poetry, 1981-2004, Subseries 2.4; Box 28, 79 and OP 164
    The subseries consists of children's poetry written by Paul Muldoon from 1981-2004. The subseries documents the writing and publication of all four of Muldoon's children's collections: The O-O's Party, The Last Thesaurus, The Noctuary of Narcissus Batt, and Reverse Flannery. Also included is a small amount of uncollected children's poetry.
    Arranged by volume.
    - The O-O's Party (1981)
    - The O-O's Party, title page with holograph note (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - The O-O's Party, typescript with holograph corrections (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - The O-O's Party, uncorrected typescript with title page (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - The Last Thesaurus (1995)
    - The Last Thesaurus, notebook with 11 pages of holograph notes (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - The Last Thesaurus, partial typescript with holograph corrections (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - The Last Thesaurus, partial typescript with holograph corrections (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - The Last Thesaurus, partial typescript with light holograph corrections (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - The Last Thesaurus, partial uncorrected typescript (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - The Last Thesaurus, corrected typescript (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - The Last Thesaurus, partial corrected typescript with holograph notes (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - The Last Thesaurus, typescript in binder with rejection letter from agent (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - The Last Thesaurus, photocopy of final typescript (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - The Last Thesaurus, complete typescript with illustrations (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - The Last Thesaurus, page proofs, one of two (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - The Last Thesaurus page proofs, two of two (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - The Noctuary of Narcissus Batt (1997) [variant title: The Notebook of Narcissus Batt]
    - Preliminary typescript with extensive holograph notes (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Typescript, 1996 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Proofs and photocopies of illustrations, 1996 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Reverse Flannery (2003)
    - Typescripts (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Proofs, October 24, 2002 (Box OP164)
    - Uncollected children's poetry
    - "Cricketty Wee," typescripts, circa 2004 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - "Mr and Mrs Narcissus Batt," typescripts (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - "Narcissus Batt at the Belfast Bank," typescript (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Untitled poem (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Prose, 1970s-2004, Subseries 2.5; Box 29, 80-83 and OP 5-9
    The subseries consists of Muldoon's prose writings from the 1970s-2004, including complete typescripts for The Faber Book of Beasts, and The End of the Poem: Oxford Lectures in Poetry; and extensive number other essays and lectures; reviews of books and movies; and scripts for the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC). Also included are a number introductions for readings by other writers.
    Arranged in alphabetical order by type of writing.
    - Prose
    - "A Tight Wee Place in Armagh," photocopy of Muldoon essay in Fortnight, July/August 1984 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - "The Creative Writing Program of Princeton University," report for the External Review Committee, October 1995 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - "Dictionary Entries," for The Future Dictionary of America, edited by Jonathan Safran Foer, circa April 2004 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - The Faber Book of Beasts, complete typescript [1 of 3] (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - The Faber Book of Beastss, complete typescript [2 of 3] (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - The Faber Book of Beasts, complete typescript [3 of 3] (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - The Faber Book of Beasts, contents, introduction, and index, typescripts, 1998 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - The Faber Book of Beasts, "Introduction," typescripts (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - The Faber Book of Beasts, typescripts of included poems [1 of 2] (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - The Faber Book of Beasts, typescripts of included poems [2 of 2] (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - "Ice" and other sketches, typescript sent to C.K. Williams, circa January 1997 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - "Making Hay," typescript, 1998 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Notes for Chez Moy: A Critical Autobiography, two typescripts (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - "Old Spice," multiple typescript drafts with holograph corrections (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - "Paul Muldoon on The Annals of Chile," typescript, 1998 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Scripts: British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC)
    - Explorations II: Secondary English: Seamus Heaney, typescript (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Explorations II: Secondary English: Ted Hughes, typescript (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - "Seamus Heaney: Teacher's Notes," typescript (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - "Ted Hughes: Teacher's Notes," typescript (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - "Time for Verse," corrected typescript drafts of scripts 1 through 4 with cover page and photocopy of review (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Reviews
    - "Barbie, but no Bimbo," review of Pocahontas, photocopy of annotated page proof, October 5, 1995 [See also: OP7 Pocahontas, review entitled "Barbie, but no Bimbo"] (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Belfast: An Illustrated History, by Jonathan Bardon, review entitled "Making the Most of a Desert Island," photocopy of corrected typescript with clipping of review from Fortnight, December 1982 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Blurbs on books by Dickinson, Hofmann, and Szymborska, typescripts, 1999 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Books of the Year blurbs for the Times Literary Supplement, typescripts, 1997-2004 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Cinema and Ireland, by Kevin Rockett, Luke Gibbons, and John Hill, typescript with light holograph corrections (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Derek Walcott's Collected Poems, clipping from The Cambridge Review, March 1987 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - "Flinging Open a Great Window," review of R.F. Foster's W.B. Yeats: A Life II: The Arch-Poet 1915-1939, typescript (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - Gaudette, by Ted Hughes, clipping from Fortnight, Friday June 10, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Dances With Wolves, review entitled "Western Ways" [variant title "Is the Western Possible?"], two clippings from TLS, February 8, 1991 (Box OP5)
    - "Imprisoned Larks," review of The New Oxford Book of Children's Verse, edited by Neil Philip, typescript (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Irish Journal, by Heinrich Böll, blurb for "Forgotten Works" project, typescript, 1999 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Irish Journal, by Heinrich Böll, review entitled "Heinrich on the Boll," clipping from Fortnight, May 1983 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - James Joyce, Ulysses and Finnegans Wake, typescripts (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - The Last of the Mohicans, review entitled "The Night of the Big Hair," typescript (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - The Midnight Court, by Brian Merriman, review entitled "Courting Couplets," clipping from The Irish Press, December 18, 1982 (Box OP6)
    - Mountain Interval, by Robert Frost, for "Books of the Century" project, typescript, 1999 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Pocahontas, review entitled "Barbie, but no Bimbo" [variant title "From Degeneration to Barbieism"], clipping from TLS, October 15, 1995 (Box OP7)
    - "Prudence Farmer Poetry Prize," clipping from The New Statesman, September 18, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - The Rattle of the North, edited by Patricia Craig, review entitled "Colcannonical," typescript (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Richard Ellmann Prize, typescript (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - The Right and Lucky Man: Selected Letters of Raymond Chandler, edited by Frank MacShane, typescript (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Seamus Heaney's Station Island and Sweeney Astray, with Craig Raine's Rich, review entitled "Sweaney Peregraine," clipping from The London Review of Books, November 1-14, 1984 (Box OP8)
    - Visitor's Book, review entitled "A Book of Evasions," clipping from The London Review of Books, March 20, 1980 (Box OP9)
    - William Faulker, for "Millennium Reputations" project, typescript, 1999 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Introductions for readings by others
    - Ashbery, John, April 11, 1998 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Dunn, Stephen and Charles Wright, typescript (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Grennan, Eamon and James Lasdun, corrected typescript (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Heaney, Seamus, [circa 1995, pre-Nobel Prize], corrected typescript (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Princeton University, April 26, 1998, typescripts (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Hughes, Robert, lightly corrected typescript (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Kinnell, Galway, July 29, 2002 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Komunyakaa, Yusef, Princeton University, September 20, 1995, typescript (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Longley, Edna, Princeton University, April 28, 1998, typescript (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Lowrie, Mark, Princeton University, February 8, 1995, typescript (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Mahon, Derek, Princeton University, [ca. 1991], lightly corrected typescript (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Milosz, Czeslaw, Princeton University, [1992-93], corrected typescript (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Morrison, Toni, Dublin International Writer's Festival, 1993, typescript (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Ní Dhomhnaill, Nuala, Princeton University, March 3 [no year] (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Turow, Scott, November 29, 2000, typescript (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - "Varsity," reading by students at Oxford and Cambridge, University of Oxford, no date (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - Wallace-Crabbe, Chris, 92nd Street Y, lightly corrected typescript (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Wilbur, Richard, Althea Ward Clark Reading Series at Princeton University, September 21, 1994, typescript (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Lectures and Essays
    - "Abschrift der Ansprache von Paul Muldoon," typescript, August 2004 (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - "The Celtic Tiger," typescript (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - "Diary," typescript and page proofs, circa 1999 (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - "The Dichter-Scale," remarks by Paul Muldoon in the Poetry and History Discussion, Cracow, October 5, 1997, typescript (Box 81, Folder 19)
    - Eliot Centenary Talk, notes (Box 81, Folder 20)
    - The End of the Poem: Oxford Lectures in Poetry, complete typescript, circa 2006 [1 of 4] (Box 81, Folder 21)
    - The End of the Poem: Oxford Lectures in Poetry, complete typescript, circa 2006 [2 of 4] (Box 81, Folder 22)
    - The End of the Poem: Oxford Lectures in Poetry, complete typescript, circa 2006 [3 of 4] (Box 81, Folder 23)
    - The End of the Poem: Oxford Lectures in Poetry, complete typescript, circa 2006 [4 of 4] (Box 81, Folder 24)
    - The End of the Poem: Oxford Lectures in Poetry, "'All Souls' Night' by W.B. Yeats," an Inaugural Lecture delivered before the University of Oxford, November 2, 1999, typescript (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - The End of the Poem: Oxford Lectures in Poetry, "'All Souls' Night' by W.B. Yeats," proofs and notes (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - The End of the Poem: Oxford Lectures in Poetry, "'All Souls' Night' by W.B. Yeats," typescript (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - The End of the Poem: Oxford Lectures in Poetry, "'I Remember' by Stevie Smith," typescript (Box 82, Folder 4)